SEAN HARRIGAN

EPIDEMIOLOGY, RESEARCH AND DATA SCIENCE

CONTACT
ORCiD: 0000-0001-6021-7402
sean.pat.harrigan@gmail.com
seanharrigan.github.io/website/
Vancouver, BC
SKILLS
RESEARCH METHODS
DATA SICENCE
STATISTICS
SCIENTIFIC WRITING
EDUCATION
MSc, Population and Public Health
University of British Columbia
2019-2021
BSc Biology, Minor Statistics
BSc Biology, Minor Statistics University of Victoria
BSc Biology, Minor Statistics University of Victoria 2013-2017
BSc Biology, Minor Statistics University of Victoria
BSc Biology, Minor Statistics University of Victoria 2013-2017 CERTIFICATES Machine Learning and AI (2023)
BSc Biology, Minor Statistics University of Victoria 2013-2017 CERTIFICATES Machine Learning and AI (2023) University of Toronto (9 mos.)
BSc Biology, Minor Statistics University of Victoria 2013-2017 CERTIFICATES Machine Learning and AI (2023) University of Toronto (9 mos.) Data Science (2022)
BSc Biology, Minor Statistics University of Victoria 2013-2017 CERTIFICATES Machine Learning and AI (2023) University of Toronto (9 mos.)
BSc Biology, Minor Statistics University of Victoria 2013-2017 CERTIFICATES Machine Learning and AI (2023) University of Toronto (9 mos.) Data Science (2022)
BSc Biology, Minor Statistics University of Victoria 2013-2017 CERTIFICATES Machine Learning and AI (2023) University of Toronto (9 mos.) Data Science (2022) University of British Columbia (9 mos.)
BSc Biology, Minor Statistics University of Victoria 2013-2017 CERTIFICATES Machine Learning and AI (2023) University of Toronto (9 mos.) Data Science (2022) University of British Columbia (9 mos.) LANGUAGES
BSc Biology, Minor Statistics University of Victoria 2013-2017 CERTIFICATES Machine Learning and AI (2023) University of Toronto (9 mos.) Data Science (2022) University of British Columbia (9 mos.) LANGUAGES R

ABOUT ME

I am a dedicated and passionate worker who loves to learn. My background includes various research roles related to health in academia, industry and volunteer positions, with a focus in methodology, data / statistical analysis and academic writing. I have a passion for health science research as well as data science, specifically data analysis and data visualisaiton.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Epidemiologist

BC Centre for Disease Control

2021-Present

- Focused on design and methodology of research projects, data and statistical analysis, and scientific writing
- Conceptualising and conducting all aspects of epidemiologic research studies (i.e. hypotheses, study population, methodology, analysis, etc.)
- Leading the statistical analysis in R, including exploratory analyses as well as creating data analysis pipelines from tidying raw data, applying causal frameworks and to modelling severity outcomes
- Leading the scientific writing of manuscripts for internal use and for publication in scientific journals

Researcher & Primary Data Analyst

University of British Columbia

2020-2021

- Initiative focused in occupational health and safety oh health workers, in Vancouver at the start of the COVID-19 pandemic
- Co-lead a study in collaboration with the World Health
 Organization which surveyed health care workers from around
 world about risks and protection measures in the workplace
 during the pandemic
- Created a database of all physicians and collect data on exposures and test results to monitor physicians and other healthcare workers in Vancouver throughout the pandemic

Research Associate

Broadstreet Health Economics and Outcomes Research 2

2017-2019

- Co-lead a systematic review on a rare disease and have coauthored a meta-analysis on drug effectiveness
- Conducted a systematic literature review and network metaanalysis, including abstract review and data extraction
- Collaborator and pharmaceutical clients in relation to the research projects
- Completed 2 courses from York University in Health Economic Modelling in R: decision analysis and Markov models (10 weeks)